<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Roverdi's Website</title><link>https://roverdiani.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Roverdi's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://roverdiani.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>WoW Arduino Fisher</title><link>https://roverdiani.github.io/posts/wow-arduino-fisher/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://roverdiani.github.io/posts/wow-arduino-fisher/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>So&amp;hellip; I made a thing.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://roverdiani.github.io/img/wowfisher.png">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;p>&lt;strong>DISCLAIMER:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>This project is intended only as a learning exercise. Don&amp;rsquo;t use it to take advantage in the game, and don&amp;rsquo;t try it on Blizz&amp;rsquo;s live servers. Automation of gameplay is against the rules, and you could lose your account. Try it on a private server if you wish to see it working.&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having said that, let me start by telling you the motivation behind this idea. At some point in my life as a WoW player (almost 12 years now), I began to collect achievements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Windows XP on a Dell Optiplex 380</title><link>https://roverdiani.github.io/posts/optiplex-380-win-xp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 20:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://roverdiani.github.io/posts/optiplex-380-win-xp/</guid><description>&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s the best way to enjoy some free time off work? By spending hours working on a dumb old computer!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, I was in need for an Windows XP era machine to play with some old games source code, and got my hands on this little Dell machine: the desktop version of the &lt;strong>Dell Optiplex 380&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://roverdiani.github.io/img/Dell-OptiPlex-380.webp">&lt;figcaption>
 &lt;h4>Mine is the model on the middle - sorry about the low quality, this is the biggest image that I found.&lt;/h4>
 &lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>

&lt;p>Before I rant about the problems that I had, let me say that I &lt;em>really&lt;/em> like this form factor: it is relatively thin, can be used on the horizontal and has a decent spec (for the purpose I will be using it for, anyway). My machine has an &lt;em>&lt;strong>Intel Core 2 Duo E7500 (2.93 GHz)&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>, &lt;strong>4 GB of &lt;em>RAM&lt;/em>&lt;/strong> and I put a &lt;strong>120 GB &lt;em>SSD&lt;/em>&lt;/strong> on it; it has an &lt;em>DVD drive&lt;/em> and &lt;em>no floppy disk drive&lt;/em> (more on that later).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SDL2, VMware, Linux and Relative Mouse Mode</title><link>https://roverdiani.github.io/posts/sdl-vm-relative-mouse-mode/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 15:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://roverdiani.github.io/posts/sdl-vm-relative-mouse-mode/</guid><description>&lt;p>So, one of my pet projects is a game engine based on a 3D Software Renderer (that I will post about some other day). One night, while I was working on it implementing an FPS camera, I started getting strange results when moving the mouse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My development setup for this kind of stuff consisted on a VM running Fedora XFCE Spin, where I would code using CLion, build and execute the program. All was working fine until I got to the mouse related code.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>https://roverdiani.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 13:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://roverdiani.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hey there! Welcome to my website!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know that this &amp;ldquo;Hello, World!&amp;rdquo; thing is really cliche, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t miss the opportunity :P&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, seriously now! My name is Rodrigo Verdiani (aka Roverdi), and I&amp;rsquo;m a Brazilian developer. You can find more about me on the &lt;a href="https://roverdiani.github.io/about">about section&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On this website I hope to post some stuff that I&amp;rsquo;m currently messing with, but for the moment I&amp;rsquo;m still working on structuring this blog. Besides that, being pretty new to this kind of thing, I&amp;rsquo;m still very shy :)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ABOUT</title><link>https://roverdiani.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roverdiani.github.io/about/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="hey-there">Hey there!&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Hey, I&amp;rsquo;m Rodrigo Verdiani, and this is my blog! :D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m a &lt;del>twenty-something&lt;/del> Brazilian tech enthusiast, currently working as a frontend developer, specializing in React.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was born in the countryside of São Paulo, Brazil, about 50 km away from the capital, and grew up mostly with my grandparents. My grandpa was a science teacher and later a programmer for the city&amp;rsquo;s water department. He’s the one who got me into computers and electronics!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CONTACT</title><link>https://roverdiani.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://roverdiani.github.io/contact/</guid><description>&lt;p>Feel free to reach me by sending a DM on any of my social networks - you can find the links on the footer of the website.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>